Inventory of the Paul B. Henze papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- 2014 December Incremental Materials (Box 217-264)
  - Correspondence, travel documentation, and writings, 1947-2010
    - Alula Aberra, 2006-2010 (Box-folder 225: 9)
    - Ian Campbell, 2007-2011 (Box-folder 225: 10)
    - Atikilti Hagege, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 226: 1)
    - Prince Afsa-Woosen Asserate, 1990-2010 (Box-folder 226: 2-3)
    - Letters received, 2000-2009 (Box-folder 226: 4)
    - Letters, 2009-2010 (Box-folder 226: 5)
    - Correspondence regarding the United States, 2005-2010 (Box-folder 226: 6-7)
    - Across Asia, 1998 (Box-folder 226: 8)
    - "Nationalism and Communism" by Paul B. Henze, 1979 (Box-folder 227: 1)
    - Reviews of Turkish and Turkey related books (Box-folder 227: 2)
    - Bibliographies (Box-folder 227: 3)
    - Ralph W. Rimbach, 2009-2010 (Box-folder 227: 4)
    - Trip to Georgia (Box-folder 227: 5)
    - Trip to Poland, 1991-2003 (Box-folder 227: 6-7)
    - Polish pamphlets and maps (Box-folder 227: 8-10)
      Includes travel pamphlets, small booklets, and magazines regarding Kraków.
    - Polish pamphlets and maps (Box-folder 228: 1-2)
    - Stanislaw Chonjacki, 2008-2010 (Box-folder 228: 3-4)
    - Haggai Erlich, 1981-2003 (Box-folder 228: 5-11)
    - Haggai Erlich, 2004-2010 (Box-folder 229: 1-3)
    - Ralph E. Walter, 2004-2010 (Box-folder 229: 4-7)
    - S. Enders Wimbush curriculum vitae (Box-folder 229: 8)
    - Washington Times, 1995 (Box-folder 229: 9)
    - ABC News, 1983 (Box-folder 229: 10)
    - NBC News, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 229: 11)
    - Inal Kitabevi (Istanbul), 1976-1998 (Box-folder 229: 12)
    - ISIS Istanbul, 1990 (Box-folder 229: 13)
    - Who's Who in America, 1972-1999 (Box-folder 229: 14)
    - Publishing houses, 1974-1985 (Box-folder 230: 1)
    - Articles and correspondence, 2000 (Box-folder 230: 2)
    - IREX reviews, 2002 (Box-folder 230: 3)
    - CWIHP/National Security Archive, 1954-1996 (Box-folder 230: 4)
    - "Uzbekistan Viewed from Fergana" by Paul B Henze (Box-folder 230: 5)
    - Miscellaneous articles, 1992-2002 (Box-folder 230: 6)
    - General correspondence, 2001-2003 (Box-folder 230: 7-10)
    - Travel emails/faxes, 2003 July-August (Box-folder 231: 1)
    - General correspondence, 2003-2006 (Box-folder 231: 2-8)
    - General correspondence, 2006-2007 (Box-folder 232: 1-3)
    - Paul B. Henze fan mail, 1983-2000 (Box-folder 232: 4-5)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 232: 6-9)
    - Articles and writings by Paul B. Henze, 1983-2005 (Box-folder 233: 1)
    - Transcribed diary regarding trip to Poland, 2003 (Box-folder 233: 2)
    - "End of Empire? End of Illusions" by Paul B. Henze, 1989 (Box-folder 233: 3)
    - Papers from the Problems of Communism Conference, 1991 (Box-folder 233: 4)
    - Transcribed diary regarding trip to Georgia, 1995 (Box-folder 233: 5)
    - "Dagestan in October 1997" by Paul B. Henze (Box-folder 233: 6)
    - "Eastern Europe: Past and Present, Future Prospects,", 1986 (Box-folder 233: 7)
    - "The Monasteries of Mertule Maryam: Speculations about Its Architectural History" and "Christianization of Gojam,", 1997 (Box-folder 233: 8)
    - "Consolidation of Christianity in the Region of the Source of the Blue Nile,", 1997 (Box-folder 233: 9)
    - Articles by Christopher Clapham (Box-folder 233: 10-11)
    - Papers for Ethiopians, 1992 (Box-folder 233: 12)
    - Memorandum from Isaias Afewerki, 1992 (Box-folder 233: 13)
    - Eritea, trip to Massawa, 1992 (Box-folder 233: 14)
    - "Ethiopia: The Fall of the Derg And the Beginning of Recovery Under the EPRDF" by Paul B. Henze, 1995 (Box-folder 233: 15)
    - Fax for President Meles Zenawi, 1994 (Box-folder 233: 16)
    - Correspondence with President Melese Zenawi, 1991 (Box-folder 233: 17)
    - Staatliches Museum Für Völkerkunde, 1981-2001 (Box-folder 234: 1)
    - Habtamu Mengistie, 2003-2005 (Box-folder 234: 2)
    - Altemur Kilic, 1986-2007 (Box-folder 234: 3)
    - Correspondence regarding Veronia plant, 2003-2006 (Box-folder 234: 4)
    - Cold War International History Project, 2006 (Box-folder 234: 5)
    - "Pious the First: McNuggets of Wisdom from the 19th President" by Steven F. Hayward, 2006 (Box-folder 234: 6)
    - Dr. Mulugeta Feseha, 2006 (Box-folder 234: 7)
    - "Talking to Tyrants: Missions to Siad Barre and Mengistu Haile Mariam, 1977-1978" by Paul B. Henze (Box-folder 234: 8)
    - Georgia and Caucasus, 2009-2010 (Box-folder 234: 9)
    - Turkey history, 2007-2010 (Box-folder 234: 10)
    - Putin's Russia, 2001-2008 (Box-folder 234: 11)
    - Christopher Hurst, 1995-2007 (Box-folder 234: 12)
    - Plot to Kill the Pope materials, 1981-2005 (Box-folder 235: 1-3)
    - Correspondence with John Koehler, 2005 (Box-folder 235: 4)
    - Lord, Zega and Peasant in Eastern Gojjam c. 1767-1901 by Habtamu Mengistie, 2003 (Box-folder 235: 5-6)
      Thesis presented to the School of Graduate Studies of Addis Ababa University.
    - Paper regarding Gojjam (Box-folder 235: 7-8)
    - Photos, 1997 (Box-folder 236: 1-4)
    - Tax information, 1961-1977 (Box-folder 236: 5-6)
    - Shorthand notebook, 1998 (Box-folder 237: 1)
    - Preliminary subdivision plan of the Bader/Henze property, 2000 (Box-folder 237: 2)
    - Letter to Mr. James Baker, 1991 (Box-folder 237: 3)
    - Miscellaneous materials, 1995 (Box-folder 237: 4)
    - Yugoslavia and Italy notes, 1983 (Box-folder 237: 5)
    - Copy of books (Box-folder 237: 6)
    - Conference materials, 1992 (Box-folder 237: 7)
      From Peace and Conflict in Emergent States: The Transcaucasus Conference.
    - Moshe Gammer, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 237: 8)
    - "Democracy of the Caucasus" by Paul B. Henze materials, 1991 (Box-folder 237: 9)
    - "Une République Soviétique Musulmane: Le Daghestan" (Box-folder 237: 10)
    - "Revue Des Éstudes Arméniennes,", 1977 (Box-folder 237: 11)
    - Caucasus manuscripts on history in Russian and Turkish (Box-folder 237: 12-13)
    - Russian articles, 1982 (Box-folder 237: 14)
    - "The Naqshbandi Order: A Preliminary Survey of its History and Significance" by Hamid Algar (Box-folder 238: 1)
    - "Life and Family in the Caucasus" by Mary Henze, 1980 (Box-folder 238: 2)
      Thesis presented to the faculty of Mount Holyoke College in partial fulfillment of the requirements for a Bachelor of Arts degree in History.
    - "La Formation de l'Empire Russe" by Boris Nolde (Box-folder 238: 3)
    - Articles in Russian (Box-folder 238: 4)
    - Articles regarding Soviet economic aid, trade, and arms traffic (Box-folder 238: 5)
    - Maoizm - "Ugroza Afrike" by T.L. Deich, 1972 (Box-folder 238: 6)
    - Miscellaneous articles regarding Armenia (Box-folder 238: 7)
    - Miscellaneous articles regarding Georgia (Box-folder 238: 8)
    - "MS Lazarev Kurdski Voppos,", 1973 (Box-folder 238: 9)
      Materials in Russian.
    - "Sovetskaya Diplomatia I Narody Vostoka 1921-1927,", 1968 (Box-folder 238: 10)
    - Articles regarding Turkey (Box-folder 238: 11)
    - Articles regarding Soviet nationalities (Box-folder 238: 12)
    - L.N. Gumilev "Ancient-Turks,", 1967 (Box-folder 238: 13)
    - Articles regarding Turkey, 1973 (Box-folder 238: 14)
    - Article in Russian (Box-folder 238: 15)
    - Article in Russian (Box-folder 239: 1)
    - "History of Dagestan,", 1968 (Box-folder 239: 2)
    - "Caucasus in the Crimean War,", 1971 (Box-folder 239: 3)
    - Article in Russian, 1989 (Box-folder 239: 4)
    - "Kurdish Uprising,", 1966 (Box-folder 239: 5)
    - "Le Mouvement National Kurde,", 1979 (Box-folder 239: 6)
      Materials in French.
    - "Fight for Kurdistan,", 1963 (Box-folder 239: 7)
    - "Goal: Stabilization, Soviet Agitational Propoganda, Instability and Terrorism in NATO South" by Paul B. Henze, 1981 (Box-folder 239: 8)
    - "Defending the Upper Gulf: Turkey's Forgotton Partnership" by Marcy Agmon, 1983 (Box-folder 239: 9)
    - 202 Jokes of Nasreddin Hodja (Box-folder 240: 1)
    - "Turkey in mid-1976" (Box-folder 240: 2)
    - Symposium on Continuity and Change Conference pamphlet, 1992 (Box-folder 240: 3)
    - Articles regarding Turkey, 1976-1988 (Box-folder 240: 4)
    - Correspondence and articles regarding Turkey, 1977-1982 (Box-folder 240: 5)
    - Ankara country team meeting notes, 1976 (Box-folder 240: 6)
    - "Immortal Ataturk: Narcissism and Creativity" by Vamik D Volkan, 1977 (Box-folder 240: 7)
    - "Hadjin, and the Armenian Massacres" (Box-folder 240: 8)
    - Articles regarding Turkey, 1979-1996 (Box-folder 240: 9-10)
    - The Ancient Olympic Games by Judith Swaddling, 1980 (Box-folder 241: 1)
    - Articles regarding Turkey, 1982-1986 (Box-folder 241: 2)
    - "Soviety Nationalities in German Wartime Strategy, 1941-1945" by Alex Alexiev, 1982 (Box-folder 241: 3)
    - "Turkey: Toward the Twenty-First Century" by Paul B. Henze, 1992 (Box-folder 241: 4)
    - "Turkish Democracy and the American Alliance" by Paul B. Henze, 1993 (Box-folder 241: 5)
    - Materials regarding Turkey, 1982-1985 (Box-folder 241: 6-9)
    - Turkey Postscript, Turkish Times version, 1976-2000 (Box-folder 242: 1)
    - Miscellaneous conferences, seminars, and notes, 1988 (Box-folder 242: 2)
    - Washington Institute Turkey Conference, 1997 (Box-folder 242: 3)
    - Science Applications International Corporation Turkey Conference, 1996 (Box-folder 242: 4)
    - "What Ataturk Did Not Do" by Paul B. Henze, 1998 (Box-folder 242: 5)
    - Turkey Postscript, 1999 (Box-folder 242: 6)
    - "American Policy Toward the Soviet Union: Fundamentals and Imperatives" by Paul B. Henze (Box-folder 242: 7)
    - Interview with Turkish Times, 1989 (Box-folder 242: 8)
    - "Progress and Disorder: 75 Years of the Turkish Republic" by Andrew Mango, 1999 (Box-folder 242: 9)
    - Turkey papers, 1997 (Box-folder 242: 10)
    - "The Fate of the Muslims" manuscript review, 1988 (Box-folder 242: 11)
    - "Turkey, the United States and the Armenian Issue: Reflections on the Recent Mini-Crisis" by Paul B. Henze, 1984 (Box-folder 242: 12)
    - Conference on Turkey Under Ozal, 1985 (Box-folder 242: 13)
    - Interview with Turkish newspapers, 1989 (Box-folder 242: 14)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, study group on Turkey, 1984 (Box-folder 243: 1)
    - Map of Turkey, undated (Box-folder 243: 2)
    - "Turkish Houses" pamphlet, 1990 (Box-folder 243: 3)
    - Welcome to Kazakstah phrasebook, 1991 (Box-folder 243: 4)
    - Turkish World Phrase Guide for Travellers, 1992 (Box-folder 243: 5)
    - Travel pamphlets from Rome, undated (Box-folder 243: 6)
    - Radio Free Europe pamphlet and scholarly article, 1990s (Box-folder 243: 7)
    - Scholarly articles regarding communism and Soviet Russia, 1989-1998 (Box-folder 243: 8-9)
    - Review of Archaeology, Volumes 10-13, 1989-1994 (Box-folder 243: 10)
    - Memorandum to Dr. Brzezinski from Martin Strmecki regarding a trip to the Soviet Union, 1989 (Box-folder 243: 11)
    - Clippings, scholarly articles, and correspondence, 1990-1995 (Box-folder 243: 12)
    - Encounter magazine, 1984 (Box-folder 243: 13)
    - Memorandum, correspondence, and clippings regarding Ethiopia, 1989-1995 (Box-folder 244: 1)
    - Poems: Father and Son manuscript by Edmund P. Murray and Patrick C. Murray, 1987 (Box-folder 244: 2)
    - Central Asian Foundation correspondence, 1993-1998 (Box-folder 244: 3)
    - The World Bank Atlas, 1985 (Box-folder 244: 4)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 244: 5)
    - Correspondence, articles and pamphlets, 1983-1991 (Box-folder 244: 6)
    - Press releases from the Bulgarian Embassy, 1983 (Box-folder 244: 7)
    - Correspondence, clippings, and articles, 1983 (Box-folder 244: 8)
      Includes materials in Russian.
    - On the Wolf's Track by Iona Andronov, 1983 (Box-folder 244: 9)
    - A Subversion of the Neo Crusaders by Bulgarian Telegraph Agency and the Sofia Press Agency, 1983 (Box-folder 244: 10)
    - Ben Mesih, undated (Box-folder 244: 11)
    - Free Antonov! by Bulgarian Telegraph Agency and the Sofia Press Agency, 1983 (Box-folder 244: 12)
    - The Anatomy of a Slander Campaign by Sofia Press Agency, 1983 (Box-folder 244: 13)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1983-1992 (Box-folder 244: 14)
    - Maps of the People's Republic of China and the Soviet Union, undated (Box-folder 244: 15)
    - Soviet Military Power, 1981 (Box-folder 245: 1)
    - Bay of Pigs by Albert C. Persons, 1968 (Box-folder 245: 2)
    - Ramparts magazine, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 245: 3)
    - Man's Ancestors: An Introduction to Primate and Human Evolution by Ian Tattersall, 1970 (Box-folder 245: 4)
    - Clippings, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 245: 5)
    - "From Moscow to Peking in the Era of Glasnost and Perestroika" by Paul B. Henze (Box-folder 245: 6)
    - Personal correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 245: 7)
    - Scholarly articles and clippings, 1986-1995 (Box-folder 245: 8)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box-folder 246: 1)
    - Turkish newspaper clippings, 1986 (Box-folder 246: 2)
    - Articles, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 246: 3)
    - Correspondence and scholarly articles, undated (Box-folder 246: 4)
    - Phone messages, postcards, business cards, and notes, undated (Box-folder 246: 5)
    - Miscellaneous notes on history and writings, undated (Box-folder 246: 6)
    - Personal correspondence, 1947-1962 (Box-folder 246: 7-9)
    - Addis Ababa historical papers (Box-folder 246: 10)
    - Letters written in unidentified language, 1947 (Box-folder 246: 11)
  - Diary transcripts, 1947-1999
    Contains transcripts from diaries written in shorthand.
    - From Cambridge to Delano, 1948 December 17-20 (Box-folder 246: 12)
    - Ethiopia travels, 1984 November-December (Box-folder 246: 13)
    - Mongolia travels, 1989 June 14-24 (Box-folder 246: 14)
    - Mission to Chechnia, 1992 September-October (Box-folder 246: 15)
    - Ethiopia and Eritrea, 1993 April 22-27 (Box-folder 246: 16)
    - Notes from United States Information Agency speaking tour of Western Europe, 1993 September-October (Box-folder 246: 17)
    - Eritrea and Ethiopia, 1995 January-April (Box-folder 246: 18)
    - Georgia, 1995 May-June (Box-folder 247: 1)
    - Ethiopia, 1996 March 26 (Box-folder 247: 2)
    - Xinjiang, 1996 August 8-12 (Box-folder 247: 3)
    - Tigray Rock Church notes, 1997 March 26-28 (Box-folder 247: 4)
    - Georgia, 1997 May-June (Box-folder 247: 5)
    - Caucasus travels, 1997 November 2 (Box-folder 247: 6)
    - Ethiopia, 1998 February 9-28 (Box-folder 247: 7)
    - Across Asia, 1998 June-July (Box-folder 247: 8)
    - Addis Ababa, 1999 April (Box-folder 247: 9)
  - Diaries, 1941-1998
    Contains diaries written primarily in Gregg shorthand, with some notes in English, with Tower Orthography spelling.
    - 1941 December-1942 April (Box-folder 247: 10)
    - 1942 April-June (Box-folder 247: 11)
    - 1942 June-August (Box-folder 247: 12)
    - 1942 August-September (Box-folder 247: 13)
    - 1942 September-November (Box-folder 247: 14)
    - 1942 November-1943 January (Box-folder 247: 15)
    - 1943 January-February (Box-folder 247: 16)
    - 1943 February-April (Box-folder 247: 17)
    - 1943 September-December (Box-folder 247: 18)
    - 1943 December-1944 (Box-folder 248: 1)
    - 1944 January-February (Box-folder 248: 2)
    - 1944 February March (Box-folder 248: 3)
    - 1946 January-February (Box-folder 248: 4)
    - 1946 February-April (Box-folder 248: 5)
    - 1946 April-June (Box-folder 248: 6)
    - 1946 May (Box-folder 248: 7)
    - 1946 June-July (Box-folder 248: 8)
    - 1946 July-August (Box-folder 248: 9)
    - 1946 October-1947 November (Box-folder 248: 10)
    - 1946 November-1947 April (Box-folder 248: 11)
    - 1947 June-July (Box-folder 248: 12)
    - 1947 July-August (Box-folder 248: 13)
    - 1947 September-December (Box-folder 248: 14)
    - Composition book, 1948 (Box-folder 248: 15)
    - 1948 February-August (Box-folder 249: 1)
    - 1948 August-November (Box-folder 249: 2)
    - 1948 November-1949 March (Box-folder 249: 3)
    - 1949 March-June (Box-folder 249: 4)
    - 1949 September-March (Box-folder 249: 5)
    - 1950 July (Box-folder 249: 6)
    - Notes, 1951 (Box-folder 249: 7)
    - Notes, 1952 (Box-folder 249: 8)
    - 1960 March-April (Box-folder 249: 9)
    - 1966 April-1967 March (Box-folder 249: 10)
    - 1967 March-December (Box-folder 249: 11)
    - 1968 January-December (Box-folder 249: 12)
    - 1974 November-1977 July (Box-folder 249: 13)
    - Turkish American Conference, 1981 June 15-19 (Box-folder 250: 1)
    - 1982 January-May (Box-folder 250: 2)
    - Conference notes, 1982 January 23 (Box-folder 250: 3)
    - 1982 April-June (Box-folder 250: 4)
    - 1982 April (Box-folder 250: 5)
    - 1982 April-September (Box-folder 250: 6)
    - 1982 May-July (Box-folder 250: 7)
    - 1982 July-September (Box-folder 250: 8)
    - 1982 August (Box-folder 250: 9)
    - 1982 September-October (Box-folder 250: 10)
    - 1982 October (Box-folder 250: 11)
    - 1982 October-December (Box-folder 251: 1)
    - 1982 October-1983 February (Box-folder 251: 2)
    - 1982 December-1983 April (Box-folder 251: 3)
    - Wilson Center Lectures, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 251: 4)
    - 1983 January (Box-folder 251: 5)
    - 1983 January-February (Box-folder 251: 6)
    - 1983 March-December (Box-folder 251: 7)
    - 1983 March-July (Box-folder 251: 8)
    - 1983 May (Box-folder 251: 9)
    - 1983 July-August (Box-folder 251: 10)
    - 1983 August-December (Box-folder 252: 1)
    - 1983 August-September (Box-folder 252: 2)
    - 1983 October (Box-folder 252: 3)
    - 1983 December-1984 January (Box-folder 252: 4)
    - 1984 January-December (Box-folder 252: 5)
    - 1984 January-April (Box-folder 252: 6)
    - 1984 March-July (Box-folder 252: 7)
    - 1984 April (Box-folder 252: 8)
    - 1984 May-June (Box-folder 252: 9)
    - 1984 July-September (Box-folder 252: 10)
    - Wilson Center Lectures, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 253: 1)
    - 1984 September-October (Box-folder 253: 2)
    - 1984 September-October (Box-folder 253: 3)
    - 1984 October-December (Box-folder 253: 4)
    - 1984 December-1985 February (Box-folder 253: 5)
    - 1985 January-December (Box-folder 253: 6)
    - 1985 January-February (Box-folder 253: 7)
    - 1985 February-May (Box-folder 253: 8)
    - 1985 May-June (Box-folder 253: 9)
    - 1985 June-July (Box-folder 253: 10)
    - 1985 July-August (Box-folder 253: 11)
    - 1985 October-December (Box-folder 254: 1)
    - 1985 October-November (Box-folder 254: 2)
    - 1986 January-December (Box-folder 254: 3)
    - 1986 January-February (Box-folder 254: 4)
    - 1986 January-December (Box-folder 254: 5)
    - 1986 February-May (Box-folder 254: 6)
    - 1986 March-April (Box-folder 254: 7)
    - 1986 May-July (Box-folder 254: 8)
    - 1986 July-September (Box-folder 254: 9)
    - 1986 August-December (Box-folder 254: 10)
    - 1986 October-November (Box-folder 254: 11)
    - 1986 December (Box-folder 255: 1)
    - 1987 January-December (Box-folder 255: 2)
    - 1987 January-February (Box-folder 255: 3)
    - Wilson Center Lectures, 1987 January 8-21 (Box-folder 255: 4)
    - 1987 February-July (Box-folder 255: 5)
    - 1987 April (Box-folder 255: 6)
    - 1987 June (Box-folder 255: 7)
    - Wilson Center Lectures, 1987 June 18-20 (Box-folder 255: 8)
    - 1987 June-July (Box-folder 255: 9)
    - 1987 October-November (Box-folder 255: 10)
    - 1987 December (Box-folder 255: 11)
    - 1988 January-March (Box-folder 255: 12)
    - 1988 January-June (Box-folder 256: 1)
    - Wilson Center Lectures, 1988-1990 (Box-folder 256: 2)
    - 1988 March-April (Box-folder 256: 3)
    - 1988 May-September (Box-folder 256: 4)
    - 1988 June (Box-folder 256: 5)
    - 1988 July-December (Box-folder 256: 6)
    - 10th International Ethiopian Studies Conference, 1988 August 21-28 (Box-folder 256: 7)
    - Soviet-Chinese trip, 1988 September-October (Box-folder 256: 8-11)
    - 1988 September-November (Box-folder 257: 1)
    - 1988 December (Box-folder 257: 2)
    - 1989 January-December (Box-folder 257: 3)
    - 1989 January-May (Box-folder 257: 4)
    - Horn of Africa Conference, 1989 April 27-29 (Box-folder 257: 5)
    - 1989 May-August (Box-folder 257: 6)
    - 1989 June-July (Box-folder 257: 7)
    - 1989 August-November (Box-folder 257: 8)
    - 1989 September-December (Box-folder 258: 1-3)
    - 1990 January-April (Box-folder 258: 4-6)
    - 1990 May-June (Box-folder 258: 7)
      Includes notes from the Horn of Africa Conference.
    - School of Oriental and African Studies Conference at the University of London, 1990 July 15-22 (Box-folder 258: 8)
    - 1990 August-November (Box-folder 258: 9)
    - 1990 August-October (Box-folder 258: 10)
    - 1990 November-December (Box-folder 259: 1)
    - 1990 November-December (Box-folder 259: 2)
    - School of Oriental and African Studies Conference at the University of London, 1991 April 4-5 (Box-folder 259: 3)
      Conference titled "The Turkish Economy in the 1990s."
    - Notes from lectures and seminars, 1991 March-December (Box-folder 259: 4-5)
    - 1991 May-August (Box-folder 259: 6-7)
    - 1991 September-October (Box-folder 259: 8)
    - Notes from lectures and seminars, 1991 September-December (Box-folder 259: 9)
    - 1991 October-December (Box-folder 259: 10)
    - 1991 November-1992 March (Box-folder 259: 11)
    - 1992 February-December (Box-folder 260: 1)
    - 1992 March-July (Box-folder 260: 2)
    - 1992 May-June (Box-folder 260: 3)
    - 1992 July-October (Box-folder 260: 4-5)
    - 1992 September-October (Box-folder 260: 6)
    - 1993 January-December (Box-folder 260: 7)
    - 1993 January-March (Box-folder 261: 1)
    - 1993 May-September (Box-folder 261: 2-3)
    - Office of Net Assessment Summer Study Group notes, 1993 August 1-11 (Box-folder 261: 4)
    - Europe and Central Asia, 1993 September-October (Box-folder 261: 5)
    - 1993 December-1994 March (Box-folder 261: 6)
    - 1994 January-December (Box-folder 261: 7)
    - 1994 March-May (Box-folder 261: 8)
    - 1994 May-July (Box-folder 262: 1)
    - 1994 June-September (Box-folder 262: 2-3)
    - 1994 July-November (Box-folder 262: 4)
    - 1994 September-1995 January (Box-folder 262: 5)
    - 1995 March-December (Box-folder 262: 6-9)
    - 1995 May-June (Box-folder 263: 1)
    - 1995 June-December (Box-folder 263: 2)
    - 1996 January-December (Box-folder 263: 3)
    - 1996 January-February (Box-folder 263: 4)
    - 1996 April-August (Box-folder 263: 5-6)
    - 1996 July-December (Box-folder 263: 7-8)
    - Hungary and Germany, 1996 September-October (Box-folder 263: 9)
    - Hungary and the World Conference notes, 1996 September 26-29 (Box-folder 263: 10)
    - 1997 January-December (Box-folder 263: 11)
    - 1997 January-March (Box-folder 263: 12)
    - 1997 April-November (Box-folder 264: 1-2)
    - 1997 May-June (Box-folder 264: 3)
    - 1997 August-October (Box-folder 264: 4-5)
    - 1998 January-December (Box-folder 264: 5)
- Declassified U.S. Government Records, 1944-1945, 1970s-1980
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Includes some interfiled records determined by the government to be unclassified. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover.
  - May 2015 release of records, 1970s-1980 (Box-folder 264: 6-7)
    Includes material related to U.S. military and economic assistance to Ethiopia in the 1970s and a list of Ethiopians in leadership positions, as well as materials written for the National Security Council and Zbigniew Brzezinski in 1977 and 1980, and a memo on Soviet supported clandestine radios.
  - July 2015 release of records, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 264: 8)
    Memoranda and reports directed to commanding officers related to the American occupation of Monschau during World War II, particularly the military government of the U.S. zone and treatment of German civilians.